Sebastien VARRETTE, PhD

Research Associate

specialized in Distributed Platforms Security and HPC/Cloud systems.

10 years of experience in Linux HPC systems

Phone: +33(0)6 74 57 90 05 E-mail: Sebastien.Varrette@uni.lu Home page: http://varrette.gforge.uni.lu



Born on November 27th, 1979 (in France) Married (2004), two children (2007,2010)

ENGINEER EXPERTISE: High Performance Computing (HPC), Grid, Cluster & Cloud Platforms.

I'm administrating cluster-based HPC systems since 2003 (Linux environment)

Keywords: HPC, Debian, Xen, Puppet, OpenLDAP, git

MAIN RESEARCH DOMAINS: Security and Evaluation of Distributed Computing Platforms (clusters, grids or clouds).

Relevant contributions in which I'm involved:

 \bullet Code Obfuscation $% \left(1\right) =\left(1\right$

• Crash/cheating faults analysis in grid platforms

• Performance evaluation & Energy efficiency of HPC/Cloud platforms

• Design of the authentication system of Grid5000

• Developing security awareness by education

Education

2007	Ph.D. in Computer Science,	with honours (Excellent/Outstanding)	
	University of Luxembourg (UL) & Institut National Polytechnique de Grenoble (INPG)		
2003	M.Sc. in Computer Science	with honours (TB/First Class)	
	Speciality: Cryptology, Security and Information Coding	(CSCI), rank: 1st	
2003	Master's Degree in Engineering (Telecoms ENSIM	AG) with honours $(B/2.1)$	
	Speciality: Computer Sciences and Telecommunications	rank: top 10%	

Employment

2011 - now	Research Associate (UL, Luxembourg)
2007 - 2010	Scientific collaborator (UL, Luxembourg)
2004 - 2007	Research Assistant (ul., Luxembourg)
2003	System administrator (ID-IMAG, Grenoble, France)

Publications

Publication category	Quantity
PhD Thesis	1
Books	4
Magazine	1
Book Chapters	7
International journals	5
International conferences with proceedings and reviews	32
(French) national conferences with proceedings and reviews	4
International conferences with proceedings	1
International conferences with reviews	7
Masters Thesis	1
Technical Reports	8
Miscellaneous	1
Total:	72

Publis	1	Papers:76	Citations:178, Years:11	h-index:8,g-index:11	hc-index:6,hI-index:2.50	6,hI-norm:5
or Per	$_{ m sh}$	Cites/year: 16.18	Cites/paper: 2.34/0.0/0	Cites/author: 69.78	Papers/author: 29.24	Query date: 2014-03-25